Tomas Makaj

Mahopac, New York | 914-483-6097 | tmakajcoding@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Medium | Portfolio Website

Software Engineer

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and ReactJs based programming and a background in Construction Project Management. Possess strong skills in problem solving, time management and is extremely detail-oriented. Takes pleasure in addressing day-to-day problems as challenges to better my own skills.

Technologies and Languages

JavaScript, React, Redux, Python, Ruby, Rails, Django, SQL, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Postman, Sinatra, Git, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Not Shake Shack - Github

Food ordering app for restaurant brick and mortar locations.

- Utilized JWT Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Engineered functional backend database allowing it to be self-sustaining using Ruby on Rails.
- Created the frontend using ReactJs allowing the user to navigate the website and update data as needed
- Created a transparent checkout cart allowing users to remove items from cart.

Lucid Real Estate - Github

Housing app that allows a user to add homes to their portfolio

- Built a backend database using Ruby on Rails
- Enabled ReactJs front end to fetch and render all the information from the database
- Crafted a sign in modal to persist on the frontend with scroll
- Distributed different data from the database by using multiple useEffects

The Hype Hut - Github

E-Commerce app for consignment shops and small businesses

- Integrated a stripe checkout using the Stripe API
- Created the backend and database using Ruby on Rails, Postman, and PostgreSql
- Incorporated Bootstrap Carousel on the landing page
- Utilized JWT Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user email and password

EXPERIENCE

Taconic RemodelNew York, New YorkProject Manager06/2020 - 01/2022

- Managed various renovation projects.
- Coordinated all parts of the renovation process and worked with various teams to ensure completion.
- Developed and managed project timelines, resources and budget.

Majestic Home Improvement

Assistant Project Manager

New York, New York 07/2019 - 02/2020

- Assisted the project management of renovation projects.
- Consulted with clients on progress and worked with management to resolve any issues.
- Assigned and prioritized tasks for the construction team on a daily basis.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development

New York, New York 08/2022 - 11/2022

•

Fordham University

Organizational Leadership/ Bachelor of Arts

New York, New York 08/2014- 05/2018